Rickie H. Dixon Jr.

727-642-7851 | University Place, WA | rhdixon79@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | rickiedixon.com

SUMMARY

Adaptive full stack web developer with front and back end knowledge. Hard working and collaborative individual who is ready to bring an enthusiastic attitude to any work environment. Having a background in architectural design provided me with an outlet for creating projects meant to help people and environments thrive. That same passion is used to create software that enhances the user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Java
- React
- JavaScript

- HTML
- CSS
- MySQL
- MongoDB

- Django
- Spring
- Express.JS
- BootStrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ArchiNet | React 2021

- Created using React/Material-UI in which users can catalog their favorite architectural projects
- Developed back-end with Express and MongoDB for their flexible structure and ease of data access
- Implemented a user login and registration using front-end validation, Cookies and JSON Web Token for secure user experience

Handy Helper | Python

2021

2021

- Utilized Django framework to create odd jobs application that utilizes CRUD commands for jobs to be created, given away, or deleted
- Users may also add jobs from other users to their own list of jobs and mark them as done once completed
- Utilized Bcrypt and hashing for user security

Study Buddy | React

- A study timer created using React/Bootstrap based on the Pomodoro study technique
- Timer is equipped with standard functionality (i.e. start, stop and time increment/decrement/ reset)
- Users access their Spotify account (with Spotify API authenticate) to enjoy focus music while studying or working on a project

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Bellevue, WA

• Immersive Full-Stack training program in Python, Java and MERN

2021

Saint Petersburg College | A.A. in Architectural Design | Saint Petersburg, FL

• Studied conceptual and practical application of architectural design

2008

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bartender | The Matador | Tacoma, WA

2021-Present

- Increased bar sales 15% by upselling key menu items.
- Utilize multitasking skills by providing bar service and customer care in an efficient manner
- Provide training for multiple staff members ensuring adherence to established guidelines

Bartender | Ballard Annex | Seattle, WA

2019-2020

- Responsible for opening and closing duties.
- Helped curate revolving cocktail menu
- Knowledgeable of wine and beer pairings to aid dining experience

Bartender | Garage Bowl & Billiards | Seattle, WA

2016-2019

- Handled high volume bar with attention to detail
- Catered event hosting
- Keeping customer experience a top priority

Bartender | The Bends | Saint Petersburg, FL

2012-2016

- Specialized in classic and craft cocktails
- Promoted for frequent special events on social media
- Displayed wide knowledge of craft beers

Carpenter | MESH, LLC. Architecture/Fabrication | Saint Petersburg, FL

2009-2012

- Read blueprints to compile cut list and check for adequate material inventory
- Assembled and installed custom cabinetry and furniture
- Responsibly delivered finished materials on schedule